Friday, 30 November, 1962
1962年 11月30日 星期五
Waking up begins with saying "am" and "now".
起床有"想要"和"已經"之分
Jennifer, I'm not gonna tell you again.
珍妮弗 別讓我再說第二遍
For the past eight months waking up has actually hurt.
八個月以來 夢醒時分總是心痛無比
The cold realization that I'm still here slowly sets in.
我依然存活的殘酷意識 還在慢慢滲透
I was never teribly fond of waking up.
我從未真正喜歡過醒來的感覺
I was never one to jump out of bed
我也無法像吉姆一樣
and greet the day with a smile like Jim was.
微笑著起來迎接新的一天
I used to want to punch him sometimes in the morning he was so happy.
見他一大早就那麼開心 我甚至想過給他一拳
I always used to tell him that
我常跟他說
only fools greet the day with a smile...
只有愚人才會笑著迎接新一天
...that only fools possibly escape the simple truth.
...只有愚人才會對現實的一切置若惘然
That now isn't simply now.
而現在 惘然都已經不復存在
It's a cold reminder. One day later than yesterday.
就像一個冷酷的提示 日復一日
One year later than last year.
年復一年
And that sooner or later it will come.
終有一天 它會來到你的身邊
He used to laugh at me and then give me kiss on the cheek.
他總是笑而不語 輕吻我的臉頰
It takes time in the morning for me to become George.
每天早上 我要花上一段時間打扮成喬治
The time to adjust to
我需要時間來適應
what is expected of George and how he is to behave.
喬治的形象和他應有的表現
By the time I have dressed and put the final layer of polish...
待到我穿著得體 一切光彩煥然...
...on the now slightly stiff
...展現給人們一個不茍言笑
but quite perfect George...
卻栩栩如生的喬治的時候...
...I know fully what part I'm supposed to play
...我就知道自己該扮演哪個角色了...
Looking in the mirror staring back at me
注視著鏡中自己的面龐
isn't so much as a face...
可以說不是一張面孔...
...as the expression of a predicament.
...而是困境折射出來的表情
Just get through the goddamn day.
熬過這混渾渾噩噩的一天吧
A bit melodramatic, I guess.
雖然有些戲劇化...
But then again...
但說真的...
...my heart has been broken.
...我的心已經受傷了
I feel as if I am sinking, drowning...
我覺得自己在慢慢下沉 慢慢被淹沒...
...can't breathe.
...無法呼吸
Aren't you going to say something?
你不發表點見解嗎?
Are you kidding? It's spectacular.
開玩笑嗎?這簡直不可思議
What are you doing?
你要幹嘛?
Just stop it. Stop it.
別這樣 別
I don't think that you're quite ready for
我覺得你還沒準備好
life in a glass house.
住在玻璃房子裡 (諺語 公佈於眾)
Drapes, old man.
那就拉窗簾咯 老頭子
You're the one who is always saying that we are invisible.
是你一直都說我們是隱形的
That's not exactly what I meant.
我不是這個意思
For the first time in my life I can't see my future.
人生頭一回 我覺得未來如此渺遠
Every day goes by in a haze.
每天都在懵懂的迷霧中悄然度過
But today I have decided will be different.
而今天 我決定要過得迥然不同
Finally. You know it's been raining here all day.
總算打來了 今天一直都在下雨
I've been trapped in this house waiting for you to call.
我就躲在屋子裡 等著你打電話來
I'm sorry, I must have the wrong number.
抱歉 我是不是打錯了
I'm calling for Mr. George Falconer.
我要找喬治·福克納先生
I'm sorry, I was expecting someone else.
不好意思 我在等別人電話
Yes sir, you have indeed called the...
沒錯 您並...
...correct number. How may I help you?
...沒有打錯 有什麼事情嗎?
This is Harold Ackerley.
我是哈羅德·阿克利
I'm Jim's cousin.
我是吉姆的表哥
Of course. Yes, good evening Mr. Ackerley.
哦 你好啊 晚上好 阿克利先生
I'm afraid I'm calling with some bad news.
恐怕我有些噩耗要告訴您
There has been a car accident.
發生了一起車禍
An accident?
車禍?
There has been a lot of snow here lately and the roads have been icy.
最近這裡一直下雪 道路比較滑
On his way into town, Jim lost control of his car.
吉姆在進城的路上 剎車失靈了
It was instantaneous apparently.
結果 一下子人就沒了
It happened late yesterday, but his parents didn't want to call you.
是昨天晚上發生的 但他父母不想通知您
I see.
我知道了
In fact, they don't that I'm calling you now.
事實上 我現在也是背著他們打給你的
But I thought that you should know.
因為我覺得應該讓你知道
Thank you.
謝謝你
I know this must be quite a shock. It was for all of us.
我知道這對您打擊很大 我們都很悲痛
Yes, indeed.
是啊 沒錯
Will there be a service?        The day after tomorrow.
要舉行葬禮嗎?      葬禮安排在後天
Well, I suppose I should get off the phone...
那我恐怕要放下電話...
...and book a plane flight.
...趕緊訂一班飛機
The service is just for family.
葬禮僅限家人
For family, of course.
家人啊 當然
Well, thank you for calling.
那麼 謝謝你能通知我
Mr. Ackerley?        Yes?
阿克利先生?      什麼事?
May I ask what happened to the dogs?
我想問問那兩條狗怎麼處理呢?
Dogs?
狗?
There was a dog with him but he died. Was there another one?
有一條跟著他的狗也死了 還有另外一條嗎?
Yes, there was a small female.
嗯 還有一條小母狗
I don't know, I'm sorry.
這我就不清楚了 很抱歉
I haven't heard anyone mentioning another dog.
我沒聽誰提起過另外那條狗
Well, thank you for calling Mr. Ackerley.
再次謝謝您能打來告訴我
Goodbye, Mr. Falconer.
再見 福克納先生
Hello, Charley.
喂 夏莉
How did you know it was me?
你怎麼會知道是我?
Charlotte, nobody else calls me before eight in the morning.
夏洛特 不會有別人在早晨8點之前打電話來的
I didn't call too early, did I? You sound grumpy.
不會是擾了你的清夢吧? 你聽起來不大高興
No, I have a headache.
不 我只是有些頭痛
Listen, I was going to call you actually.
我本來要給你打電話的
Is it too late to change my mind about tonight.
今晚的事我改主意還來得及嗎
No, of course not.
來得及啊 怎麼來不及
I haven't seen you all week.
我只是一周都沒見你而已
I'm dying for a dose of you.        I know, I'm sorry.
我都快想死你了      我知道 實在抱歉
So great, I'll see you tonight.
那就這麼定了 今晚見
I have to run. I'm late for the work.
我先掛了 上班要遲到了
I'll call you later from school.
等會兒到了學校再打給你
Alright, I see you then.
好的 晚上見
Bye, kiddo.        Bye, old man.
再見 小淘氣      再見 大哥哥
Good morning, Mr. George.
早上好 喬治先生
Sir, you don't look so good today.
先生 您今天氣色不大好啊
Good morning, Alva. No, I didn't sleep very well.
愛爾瓦 早安 我沒事 只是沒睡好而已
You forgot to take the bread out of the freezer this morning.
你今早忘記把麵包從冰箱裡拿出來了
It stays fresh that way.
那樣才能保鮮啊
It was a little too fresh this morning.
不過今天早上有點兒太鮮了
There are some papers laid out on my desk...
我桌上有幾張紙...
...which need to stay there. Please don't move them.
...放在那兒就好 不要動
I'm afraid my pen leaked all over the bed.
抱歉我的鋼筆墨水染到床單上了
It's okay, sir.
沒關係的 先生
Alva?        Yes, sir?
愛爾瓦?      是的 先生?
Thank you, you're a wonderful.
你真好 謝謝你
This government, as promised,
正如政府承諾的
has maintained the closest surveillance...
他們會一如既往地對蘇軍在
...of the Soviet military buildup on the Island of Cuba.
...古巴島上的軍事集結進行密切監視
Within the past week unmistakable evidence...
過去幾周以來的確鑿證據...
...has established the fact...
...讓我們有理由相信...
Professor Falconer?        Yes?
福克納教授?      怎麼了?
There was a student here this morning asking for your address.
今早有個學生問我要了你的住址
My address?
我的住址?
Did you give it to him?        Yes, sir.
你給他了嗎?      是的 先生
I did.
我給了
I hope that's okay.
希望不會給您添麻煩
I realize that I probably shouldn't have but he was very nice.
之後我意識到也許不該給的 可他人真的很好
Before I knew it he...
所以我覺得他不會...
Your hair looks great up like that. I really fits suits you.
你的髮型非常漂亮 很襯你
You always look so beautiful...
你總是那麼美艷動人...
...really fresh...
...青春活潑...
You have such a lovely smile.
你笑起來很甜
Arpege?        Sir?
艾佩芝? (香水品牌)     先生?
Really beautiful.
真的很漂亮
...that a series of offensive missile sites...
...一系列具有攻擊性的導彈基地
Good morning, Don.        Good morning, George.
先生們 早上好      喬治 早上好
Good morning, George.
早上好 喬治
Good morning, Grant.
早上好 格蘭特
You look awful. What have you been doing?
你氣色不大好 怎麼了?
Look around you, Grant.
格蘭特 看看你的周圍
Most of these students aspire to nothing more than corporate job...
大多數學生都只圖畢業後能去公司裡工作
...and a desire to raise
...然後生一個
coke-drinking, TV-watching children...
喝著可樂 看著電視的小屁孩...
...who as soon as they can speak
...過不了幾年
start chanting TV jingles...
孩子就開始大唱廣告歌曲...
...and smashing things with hammers.
...拿著錘子搞破壞了
You're really scaring me today, George.
喬治 你今天怎麼不大對勁
Don't tell me. You have easy time with these students.
別跟我說 你和這些個學生相處很融洽
I found them staring at me
我發現他們看我
in a kind of bovine stupor...
像看一個喋喋不休的老先生一樣...
...as if I were lecturing in a foreign language.
...就好像我是用外語教書一般
Remind me why we shouldn't all just be annihilated.
這也提醒了我們果然不是一個世界的人
You seem to think this is all a joke.
你怎麼對什麼都一哂置之
We're living in a world where nuclear war is a real threat.
我們當前的世界 正瀰漫著核武器帶來的恐懼
I don't understand how that doesn't concern you.
我不明白為什麼你毫不關心
You're serious, aren't you?
你是認真的 對吧?
Yes, I'm serious.
是的 我很認真
George did you even read
喬治 你到底讀沒讀
the article I gave you on bomb shelters?
我給你的關於防空洞的文章?
Our is almost done. We had 3 contractors work on it...
我們基本上談妥了 現在找了三個承包商...
...so none of them know what we've got.
...所以就不會有人知道這些
I'm having the outside of it landscaped
我會依照地形而建
so no one will that it's there.
這樣就神不知鬼不覺了
Really?
是嗎?
If word gets out that you've got a better shelter...
如果傳出去說你的防空洞比別人的好...
...then everyone will try to get in when something happens.
...那等到戰亂爆發 人們就一股腦地擠過來
So?
所以呢?
There will be no time for sentiment
蘇聯的導彈扔過來
when the Russians fire a missile at us.
就沒有時間留給你多愁善感了
If it's going to be a world with no time for sentiment Grant...
格蘭特 倘若這世界沒有時間多愁善感...
...the it's not a world that I want to live in.
...那麼這也不會是我想要生活的世界
After Many a Summer
"夏去夏來天鵝死"
Dies the Swan.
(英國作家赫胥黎在1939年所寫小說)
I think you've all...
想必大家...
...read the Huxley novel
...都讀過
I assigned more than three weeks ago?
我三周前佈置的這本赫胥黎的小說了吧
How does the title relate to our story?
題目與作品有何關聯?
Yes, Mr. Mong.
蒙先生 請講
It doesn't.
並無關聯(赫胥黎引用"泰索尼斯"中的詩句)
It's about a rich guy
講述了一個富翁
who's too afraid that he's too old for this girl...
覺得自己已是垂暮 配不上那個女孩...
...and thinks that a young guy...
...而他認為年輕的男人...
Russ.
拉斯
Russ?
拉斯?
Yes, Mr. Hirsch.
請講 赫希先生
Sir, on page 79, Mr. Propter says that...
先生 在第79頁 普羅普特先生說道...
...the stupidest text in the Bible is
...聖經中最愚蠢的章節就是
they hated me without a cause.
"他們無故地恨我"(約翰福音15:25)
Does that mean the Nazis were right to hate the Jews?
這是為納粹對猶太人的憎惡開脫嗎?
Is Huxley an anti-Semite?        No.
難道赫胥黎是一名反猶分子嗎?      不
No, Mr. Huxley is not an anti-Semite.
不 赫胥黎先生並非反猶
Of course, the Nazis were wrong to hate the Jews.
而且 納粹對猶太的民族仇恨是天大的錯誤
But their hating the Jews was not without a cause.
但他們對猶太人的恨並非無緣無故
It's just that the cause wasn't real.
只是這原因並不真實存在
The cause was imagined.
憎恨的原因源於人們的臆想
The cause was fear.
真正的原因是恐懼
Let's leave the Jews out o this just for a moment.
咱們先暫且不要談論猶太的問題
Let's think of another minority. One that...
想想另一個少數派群體 那種...
One that can go unnoticed if it needs to.
那種被人視而不見的少數派
There are all sorts of minorities,
其實這世上有著各種各樣的少數派
blondes for example...
譬如金髮的人...
...or people with freckles.
...長著雀斑的人
But a minority is only thought of as one...
但是只有在少數派對多數派構成威脅時...
...when it constitutes some kind of threat to the majority.
...他們才被稱之為少數派
A real threat or an imagined one.
是真實的 還是臆想的
And therein lies the fear.
這當中便產生了恐懼
If the minority is somehow invisible...
倘若少數派不為人知被人忽略
...and the fear is much greater.
...那麼恐懼便無限放大
That fear is why the minority is persecuted.
恐懼的存在 導致少數派被迫害
So, you see there always is a cause.
所以 你們看原因總是存在的
The cause is fear.
這原因便是恐懼
Minorities are just people.
少數派其實就是普通人
People like us.
如我們一樣的普通人
I can see that I've lost you a bit.
感覺好像把你們講糊塗了
So tell you what? We're gonna forget about Mr. Huxley today...
這樣吧 咱們今天先不講赫胥黎了...
...and we're gonna talk about fear.
...我們來探討一下恐懼
Fear, after all, is our real enemy.
畢竟...恐懼才是我們真正的敵人
Fear is taking over our world.
恐懼正在吞噬著我們的世界
Fear is being used as a tool of manipulation in our society.
恐懼被用來操控著我們的社會
It's how politicians peddle policy.
這就是政客們玩弄的伎倆
It's how Madison Avenue sells us
這也就是麥迪遜大道上總有人賣給我們
things that we don't need.
不需要的東西
Think about it.
仔細想想看
Fear of being attacked.
對被襲的恐懼
Fear of that there are communists lurking around every corner.
恐懼著某個暗處隱藏著共產主義者
Fear of that some little Caribbean country...
恐懼著那些和我們生活習慣截然不同的...
...that doesn't believe in our way of life
...中美洲國家會對我們
poses a threat to us.
造成威脅(古巴危機)
Fear that black culture may take over the world.
恐懼著黑人的文化將會統領全世界
Fear of Elvis Presley's hips.
擔心貓王的屁股哪天會晃掉下來
Actually, maybe that one is a real fear.
事實上 這個很有可能成為現實
Fear that our bad breath might ruin our friendships.
恐懼著口臭會破壞我們的友誼
Fear of growing old and being alone.
恐懼著韶華逝去孑然一身
The of that we're useless and that no one cares what we have to say.
恐懼著自己一無是處 無人問津
Have a good weekend.
週末愉快
Sir! May I talk to you for a minute?
先生! 我能跟你談談嗎?
Why don't you always talk to us like that?
為什麼你之前沒有這樣跟我們講過呢?
I don't think it went over very well.
我怕你們不愛聽
Man, fear of things gets to me all the time.
老師 我經常會有對週遭的恐懼
But you can't talk about it with anyone or you just sound like a fool.
但你無法跟別人傾訴 否則會讓別人覺得你很傻
You can't even talk about it with Lois?
連跟洛伊斯都不能傾訴嗎?
I don't think she's afraid of anything.
我覺得她什麼都不怕
Everyone's afraid of something, Kenny.
每個人都有恐懼的東西 肯尼
What are you afraid of, sir?
先生 那你怕什麼?
Cars.
車
How can you live in Los Angeles and be afraid of cars?
你住在洛杉磯 怎麼能怕車呢?
Maybe you can't.
可能不能吧
Sometimes my fear of things can almost paralyze me.
有時候 我內心的恐懼會讓我慌張無力
It's like I get really panic stricken
內心糾結緊張
and I feel like I might explode or something.
生怕自己的感情會突然爆發
May I ask you a personal question, sir?
我能問您個私人問題嗎 先生?
If you like.
隨便
Do you ever get high?
你曾經嗨過嗎?
How old do I look to you?
你覺得我都多大歲數了?
Have you ever taken any drugs?
那您之前吸過毒嗎?
Of course, Kenny.
當然 肯尼
Like what?
譬如什麼?
I don't feel I should be discussing
波特先生 我覺得
this with you on campus Mr. Potter.
在校園討論這事情有點不合適吧
It's the only way I get by sometimes.
這是我解壓的唯一方式
Have you ever tried mescaline?
那您試過迷幻藥嗎?
Not my drug of choice.
倒不是我的首選
I shaved off one of my eyebrows once on mescaline.
有次吸完 我把半邊眉毛都刮掉了
Not a good look for me.
看上去不好看
Sir?        I looked in the mirror.
先生?      我對著鏡子
Big mistake if you're high on mescaline.
吸完迷幻藥看鏡子是個錯誤至極的選擇
I decided that my eyebrows were taking over my face.
我感覺我的眉毛要把整個臉都吞噬了
Before I knew it, I had shaved one off.
所以我就刮掉了一半
I wore a band-aid over my eye
我等眉毛長出來的時候
for about six weeks while my brow grew back.
被迫貼了六周的創可貼
Very embarrassing.
非常尷尬
You didn't take it again after that?
打那以後你就再沒碰過了?
Kenny, have you been listening to me?
肯尼 你有聽我說話嗎?
I shaved off my eyebrow.
我把眉毛都剃掉了啊
I wanted an experience Mr. Potter,
我只是想要體驗一下 波特先生
not a career on stage.
又不是想當台上的小丑
If you ever want to get high sir, I usually have some dope.
先生 你什麼時候想要嗨一下的話 我這兒有貨
You're really mad aren't you?
你還真是瘋了
I'm sorry, sir.
抱歉 先生
I guess you don't feel very comfortable talking like this.
或許這種交談讓你覺得不適
What makes you say that?
此話怎講?
Lois thinks you're kind of cagey. Like this morning...
洛伊斯覺得你過於小心謹慎了 就像今早...
...when you were listening to
...你不動聲色地聽
all that crap we were talking about Huxley.
我們高談闊論赫胥黎
Well, not all of you.
也不是所有人啊
I didn't notice you open your mouth once.
我記得你不是沒有開口嗎
I was watching you.
因為我在注視您
You let us ramble on and on
你總是先讓我們發表見解
and then you straighten us out.
然後你再直言不諱地解釋
But you never really tell us everything you know about something.
你卻從未主動告訴過我們你所認為的一切
Well, maybe that's true up to a point.
或許在一定程度上 你說得沒錯
It's not that I want to be cagey.
但這並不是我故意謹慎
It's just that I can't really discuss things completely openly...
只是我真的無法將所有都放開談論
...at school.
...尤其是在學校
Someone would misunderstand.
有人會誤會的
I tried that today. It didn't really work out.
就像我今天試過了 反響不是很好啊
What was it you wanted to get, sir?
你是想來買什麼嗎 先生?
Nothing. I was on my way to the dean's office.
沒什麼 我是剛好要去院長辦公室
You mean you walked all the way down here just to talk to me?
所以你走了這麼長的路就是為了跟我講話咯?
Why not?        Well...
是啊      那麼...
I think you deserve something for that, sir.
先生 我覺得我應該好好答謝你才是了
Here sir, take your pick.
看看吧 選一個 先生
It's on me.        Thank you.
我送給您      謝謝
I thought you'd probably pick blue.
我還以為你會選藍色
Why blue?
為什麼是藍色?
Isn't blue supposed to be spiritual?
藍色不是代表著靈性嗎?
What makes you think I'm spiritual?
為什麼你覺得我會有靈性?
And you? Red?
你呢? 紅色?
What is red stand for?        A lot of things.
紅色代表什麼?      那可太多了
Rage, lust.
憤怒 慾望
No kidding?
開玩笑吧啊?
Well sir, I...
那麼 先生 我...
I guess I see you around.
咱們再會啊
Hello?
喂?
What are you up to, kiddo?
小淘氣 你在幹嘛呢啊?
Just trying to finish up a book. How's your day going?
正想要讀本書 你今天過得如何啊?
Fine.
不錯
I was just leaving school
我剛好要下班了
and wanted to know if you needed anything for tonight.
想問問你今晚需不需要帶點東西
Thanks, you're sweet.
謝謝 你可真貼心
But I think I'm all set.
不過我好像不缺什麼
Be a darling and...
你如果能...
...pick up gin for me, Tangueray.
...買點杜松子酒就更好了 唐桂來牌的吧
I love the color of the bottle.
我喜歡瓶子的顏色
You love what's in it. What time do you want me?
你是喜歡瓶子裡邊的東西 你想要我幾點到?
7 would be great if that's ok with you.
要是方便的話 7點鐘最好了
Perfect. I'll see you then.
那好 到時見了
I'll see you then. Bye, Geo.
到時見 再見了 喬
Bye, kiddo.
再見 小淘氣
Beautiful.
很美
Yes, Mr. Potter?
波特先生 什麼事?
Are you going somewhere, sir?
您要去哪兒嗎 先生?
That is usually why people get into their cars.
人們開車不都是為了去哪兒嗎?
No, I mean are you going on vacation or something?
不 我是說 你是要去度假或是什麼嗎?
What?
什麼?
I saw you cleaning out your office.
我看您把辦公室都清理乾淨了?
What exactly is it that you want, Kenny?
肯尼 你到底想要幹嘛?
I was just hoping that perhaps
我只是想說
we could get together for a drink or something sometime.
找個時間 咱們可以喝一杯
Why is that?
為什麼這麼說?
I don't know, sir.
我也不清楚 先生
Because I think you might like it. And...
可能我覺得你會喜歡這樣 而且...
...because you seem as though you could use a friend.
...感覺您現在需要一個朋友的陪伴
Oh really?        Yes, sir. You do.
哦 是嗎?      是的 先生 您需要
They may be right.
或許你說得對
It will have to be another time. I'm late.
下次找機會吧 我趕時間
But thank you for the invitation.
不過謝謝你的誠摯邀請
And thank you for the talk earlier.
也謝謝你今早的那番話
And stay away from the mescaline.
別再碰迷幻藥了
Hello, Mr. Falconer.
您好 福克納先生
Hello. How are you today?        I'm fine, sir.
嗯 你好嗎?      很好 先生
Do you need to get into your box?        Yes, I do.
您需要拿保險箱出來嗎?      是的
Follow me.
請跟我來
Here you are, sir.
給您 先生
If you could please sign here...
麻煩請您在這裡簽名...
Thank you.        Thank you.
謝謝      謝謝
So explain your friend Charlotte to me.
跟我講講你那朋友 夏洛特
What would you like to know?
你都想知道什麼?
I don't know. You seem very intimate I guess.
我也不知道 聽起來你們關係很親密
Like you were once together or something.
感覺你們之前曾經是戀人
You haven't slept with her, have you?        Yes.
你沒跟她睡過嗎?      睡過
And?
然後呢?
A few times when we were young.
年輕的時候 一時衝動睡過幾次
I wouldn't say that it meant nothing to me...
當然 這不可能對我毫無意義
...but it certainly meant a great deal more to Charley.
...不過顯然這對夏莉的意義非比尋常
It was a long time ago in London.
那是很久之前在倫敦的事了
I love Charley.
我很愛夏莉
And We were very close friends but that's all.
我們是很好的朋友 就這樣
Well, I'm confused.
這我倒不明白了
If you sleep with women then why are you with me?
如果你和女人上床 那你為什麼跟我在一起?
Because I fall in love with men.
因為我會愛上男人
Because I fell in love with you.
因為我愛上了你
Anyway, doesn't everyone sleep with women when they're young?
再說了 誰沒在年輕時候 跟女人睡過啊?
I haven't.        You're joking.
我沒有      你開玩笑
No, I'm not.
不 我沒開玩笑
It was just never anything that interested me.
感覺我好像對什麼都不感興趣
Well, you're awfully
你還真是新潮啊
modern aren't you?
(50-60年代青年人對世事不關心的態度)
You know, I think that was the first thing that I noticed about you...
你知道嗎 這也是我最初注意到你的一點...
...was how sure of yourself you were.
...就是你的自信
How can you be so sure about everything at your age?
你這麼年輕怎會對一切都如此篤定?
You think I'm sure of myself?
你覺得我真的瞭解自己嗎?
Of course, you are.
當然
I'm finished now. Thank you.
我弄好了 謝謝你
Yes, Mr. Falconer?
福克納先生?
Is there something else we can help you with today?
還有什麼需要效勞的嗎?
I can't find my check book and I need some cash.
我找不到支票簿了 需要些現金
Not my day I'm afraid. Excuse me a minute.
真是運氣不佳啊 請稍等一會兒
Mommy says bushy eyebrows are pedestrian,
媽媽說濃眉的人太俗氣
but I think yours are pretty.
我覺得你的濃眉很漂亮
I think yours are pretty too.
你的也很漂亮啊
Why do you look so sad?
為何你看上去這麼傷心?
Would you like to meet Charlton Heston?
你想要見見查爾斯·赫斯頓嗎?
Ben Hur.
賓虛
He's our scorpion.
我說的是我的蝎子
Every night we throw in something new to him and watch him kill it.
每晚餵它不同的食物 看著它把它們殺死
Daddy says it's like the colosseum.
爸爸說就像是看角鬥一樣
So my brother Tom put on all the columns in here.
所以我哥哥湯姆就弄了些圓柱放進來
He wants to be a set designer.
他想當個佈景師
He hasn't eaten the spider yet...
它還沒有吃掉那只蜘蛛...
...cause he's still full from the moth we gave him last night.
...因為他還沒有消化完昨晚餵它的那只飛蛾
Daddy says he wants to throw you in to the colosseum.
爸爸說他想把你放進角鬥場去
No kidding? Why?
不是吧? 為什麼呢?
He says you're light in your loafers...
他說你是穿拖鞋的(暗指他是同性戀)
...but you aren't even wearing loafers.
可你根本沒穿拖鞋
I think my brother Tom is light in his loafers too...
我覺得我哥哥湯姆也是個穿拖鞋的...
...but he wears Keds.
...可他穿的是凱茲牌(帆布鞋)
He made me do a hair conditioning treatment on my hair with eggs.
他讓我用雞蛋給頭髮做護理
Does it look shiny?
看上去有光澤嗎?
Sweetheart, what are you doing bothering Mr. Falconer?
甜心 你怎麼在這裡打攪福克納先生呢?
She's not bothering me at all Susan. How are you?
蘇珊 她沒有打擾到我 你好啊
I'm glad to see you George.
喬治 很高興見到你
George, we're having a few people over tonight for drinks...
喬治 我們今晚請了些人來喝酒...
...and would love to have you join us if you could.
...如果你能過來 大家一定很開心
Thank you. That's very kind of you but I have plans.
謝謝你的好意 不過我另外有事了
Another time then.
那就下次吧
Jennifer, let's let Mr. Falconer get back to his banking.
珍妮弗 咱們別打擾福克納先生了
Goodbye, George.
喬治 再見
Bye, Susan. Bye, Jennifer.
再見 蘇珊 再見 珍妮弗
May I help you, sir?
先生 需要點什麼嗎?
I'd like to buy some bullets for this gun, please.
我想買這把槍用的子彈 謝謝
Yes, sir. This is a really old gun, sir.
嗯 先生 這把槍可是有年頭了啊
We have a two for one sale on handguns at the moment.
我們正在搞促銷 買二贈送一把手槍
Perhaps one for the little lady?
要不要買一把送給女士呢?
No thank you. Just the bullets, please.
不必了 我只要子彈就好了
Here you go. Anything else?
給您 還需要點什麼嗎?
No, thank you.
不用了 謝謝
That would be $2.29, sir.
一共2塊29分 先生
Thank you.
謝謝
I'm sorry. I hope she didn't growl at you.
抱歉 但願她沒衝你亂吠吧
She goes a little crazy sometimes when I have to leave her in the car.
她有時會有些失控 所以我把她放在車裡
She's perfect. What's her name?
她很漂亮 叫什麼名字?
India.
印蒂雅
Let's go there.
過去
You little baby.
來 小可愛
I used to have smooth fox terriers. You don't see them very often.
我之前也養過獵狐犬 這種狗不怎麼常見
The very smell of buttered toast.
這狗聞起來像是奶油吐司
She's still a puppy isn't she?
她還是個小狗 對吧?
Well.
那麼
Have a nice evening.        You too.
祝您晚上愉快     你也是
Good night, India.
晚安 印蒂雅
I'm sorry about that.        No, It's ok.
真不好意思      沒關係的
It's my fault. I'll get you another pack.
是我的錯 我再給你買包煙
It's ok. Don't worry.
沒關係的
No, no I insist.
不 不 我還是買吧
Thank you.
謝謝
I'm sorry about the broken glass.
謝謝 抱歉在門口打爛了瓶子
Here you go.        Thanks man.
給你      謝謝了 夥計
You want one?
要來一根嗎?
No, thanks.
不 謝謝
Actually, yes. Why not?
算了 來一根又有何妨嘛
Thank you.
謝謝
Carlos.        What did you say?
卡洛斯      你說什麼?
Carlos. You asked me my name.
卡洛斯 你問我的名字嘛
Are you okay?
你沒事吧
Yeah.
哦 沒事
Yeah, I'm sorry.
嗯 抱歉
You're really something.
(西語)你真是棱角分明
You have an incredible face.
臉龐猶如雕塑
Enjoy that. It's a great gift.
好好利用 這是上天的恩賜
Your Spanish is perfect.
你的西班牙語很不錯
Thank you.
謝謝
I should have used it more.
你應該更加好好珍惜你的外表
Well...
其實...
It's not too late.
現在也不算晚
What are you doing?
你要幹嘛?
Aren't we going somewhere?
不是要去什麼地方嗎?
No. But, thanks.
不 不過 謝謝你
You know, it's the smog
是煙霧
that makes it that color.
造就了夕陽的餘暉(洛杉磯的光化學煙霧)
I've never seen a sky like this before.
我從未見過這樣的天空
Sometimes awful things have their own kind of beauty.
有時候 醜陋也有自己獨特之美
Could I have another cigarette?
我能再來一根嗎?
Sure.
當然
Are sure that you don't want to go for a drive?        I'm sure.
你確定不想去兜兜風嗎?      我確定
Where are you from?        Madrid.
你從哪兒來?      馬德里
Madrid? How did you get here?
馬德里? 你是怎麼來這裡的
It's a long story.
說來話長
I met a guy from LA at the hotel where I worked...
我在工作的旅店認識了一個洛杉磯來的小伙子...
...who told me
...他告訴我
I could live with him and that he could get me an agent.
我可以跟他住 他可以給我找份工作
But he never realized that I have a Spanish accent.
但他沒想過 我有西班牙口音
I like your accent. You speak very well.
我喜歡你的口音 你說起來非常動聽
How did you learn English?
你怎麼學的英語?
My mom had an American boyfriend when I was little.
我小時候 媽媽有個美國男友
Is your mother in Madrid?
你媽媽現在在馬德里嗎?
Yes, she is. She cuts hair.
嗯 是的 她是理髮師
She cut my hair before I left.
她在我走之前 為我剪了頭髮
Do you like it?
你喜歡這髮型嗎?
I thought it made me look like James Dean.
我覺得 我看起來像詹姆斯·迪恩
You are better than James Dean.
你比詹姆斯·迪恩還好看
Really?
真的?
Thanks.
承蒙誇獎
No one has ever picked me up and not wanted something.
從沒有人跟我搭訕卻對我毫無企圖
I think you picked me up.
我覺得是你找我搭訕的吧
This is kind of a serious day for me.
今天對我來說是相對煩惱的一天
Come on. What could be so serious for a guy like you?
說說看 像你這樣的人怎會有煩惱?
I'm just trying to get over an old love I guess.
我是想要忘卻一位舊愛
My mother says that lovers are like buses.
我媽媽說 愛人就像是公共汽車
You just have to wait a little while and another one comes along.
只要你耐心等待 下一輛自然會來
I have to go.
我得走了
You're a nice guy.
你是個不錯的人
I hope you find...
希望你能夠找到...
...someone like you.
...和你一樣的人
Thanks.
謝謝
I'm going away.
我先走了
It's your turn to change it.
輪到你去換了
Yeah, I'm not changing it. It's your turn.
才不要 是輪到你了
Besides, you never like what I put on anyway.
再說了 我放什麼你都不喜歡的
I'll give you five dollars if you change it. I'm too old to get up.
我付你五塊錢去換 我太老了 站不起來
You're only old when it's convenient for you to be old.
你只有在能佔便宜的時候才倚老賣老
What are you reading anyway?
你在讀什麼呀
Metamorphosis
變形記 卡夫卡著
Oh God. Not that depressing crap again.
老天 又是那些無病呻吟的狗屎
It's for my class.
上課用的
What highbrow work of fiction might you be reading?
你讀的又是什麼高級小說啊
Breakfast at Tiffany's
蒂凡尼的早餐 卡波特著
Don't be so smug.
少瞧不起人
Man, what a life he has.
它的日子多好
Don't you just envy him?        Why?
真叫人羨慕     為什麼
Because he can sniff anyone's arse he wants?
因為誰的屁股它都可以湊上去?
Nice.
真高雅
No, because he just does what he wants. Like yesterday...
是因為它隨心所欲 就像昨天...
...I was standing in the front yard and Susan came over to talk.
...我站在院子前 蘇珊過來聊天
And that little brat of hers Christopher came...
她家那個小少爺克裡斯托弗...
...running over waving that damned gun of his around.
...跑來耀武揚威地搖他那把破槍
And our little dog walked right up, hiked his leg...
咱們家小狗就走過去 抬起腿...
...and peed all over Christopher's new tennis shoes.
...尿透了他的球鞋
All over Christopher actually.
老實說是尿透了他全身
And of course, I had to act like I was upset
當然 我得裝作一副很生氣的模樣
It was so perfectly executed you should have seen it.
它太神了 你真該看看
After all the times those kids have tortured that poor dog.
這隻小可憐過去被那些小孩折磨了這麼多年
I mean, you should take a lesson from him. They don't...
你真該學學它們 它們...
They don't stay up all night worrying.
它們不會徹夜不眠地思慮
They figured out
它們找出了
how to get the two of us to do exactly what they want.
一套操控我們的辦法
They are basically
認真想想 它倆基本就是
very sophisticated little parasites when you think about it.
兩隻深沉的米蟲嘛
Well, the dumbest creatures are the happiest.
最愚蠢的物種總是最快樂的
Just look at your mother.
以你媽為例
He's really just living the moment.
它真是今朝有酒今朝醉
It's like now.
就好比現在
What could be better than being tucked up here with you?
還有什麼比跟你窩在一起更好的呢
If I died right now it would be OK.
就算要我立刻死掉 也無所謂了
Well, it wouldn't be OK with me
我很有所謂
so why don't you shut up and go change the record.
所以趕緊閉嘴去換唱片吧
Good answer.
這答案不錯
You know what? I was thinking about taking them up...
你不介意的話 我下周想把它們一起
...to Denver with me next week if it's okay with you.
...帶上去丹佛
It's my mom. She loves them.
我媽愛死它們了
Probably that recognition of a similar mind.
估計是因為本是同根生吧
You stay there, old man.
您待著吧 老頭
Tie in a windsor.
請系溫莎結
No, I did not forget the gin. I'll see you in ten minutes.
我沒忘松子酒的事兒 十分鐘後見
Christopher, would you like it if I killed you?
克裡斯托弗 你說我幹掉你怎麼樣
I don't know.
不知道
If you keep this up we're going to find out.
你再這樣下去 就會知道了
So, why don't you go home and stop shooting people?
所以趕緊回家 別射人了
I'm so happy to see you.
見到你真好
Come on in.
快進來
It smells wonderful. I'm very hungry. Where is Lois?
好香啊 我好餓 路易斯呢
I gave her the night off. I'm cooking myself.
我放了她一晚假 今晚我親自下廚
You are?        Yes, I'm trying something new.
是嘛?      我試著做了點新菜品
Charley darling, "you cooking' is new.
夏莉寶貝 你下廚房本身已經夠"新鮮"的
Don't be smart.
少油嘴滑舌
I'm in a good mood tonight. I'm going to be fun.
今晚我心情好 我要盡情歡樂
I've already made two New Year's resolutions.
我已經許下新年決心了
Resolution one: No more talk that of awful ex-husbands...
決心一 再也不提我的雞巴前夫...
..and children who don't give a damn.
和沒良心的孩子了
And the other one?        One what?
還有呢      還有什麼
Resolution.
決心
Resolution two:
決心二
More smoking and more drinking and screw it all! So come on...
多喝 多抽 去他媽的 來
...mix me up a drink.
...給我調杯酒
I'll have a gin and tonic, please.
我要來杯松子酒加湯力水
And watch out baby!        Coming up.
瞧好了吧寶貝兒      馬上來
It was sweet of you to come tonight.
你今晚能來真是太體貼了
Sweet had nothing to do with it.
這跟體貼無關
I needed to see you.      Oh,Geo. Come off it.
我也需要見你      少來了
Whenever you do something sweet you're too ashamed to admit it.
每次你體貼別人時總是不好意思承認
Here is to our early New Year's resolutions.
來敬我們的新年前決心
Cheers.
乾杯
What are your resolutions by the way?
你的決心是什麼
To let go of the past completely, entirely, and forever.
完全 徹底 永遠地遺忘過去
Light me up, will you?
點根兒煙 好嗎
Darling, you don't look well.
親愛的 你氣色不對啊
Do you remember that little heart attack you had last year?
還記得你去年的那場心臟病嗎
It wasn't a heart attack.
那算不上心臟病
Well whatever it was darling...
不管那是什麼 親愛的...
...you don't look so hot.
...你現在可一點都不性感
I'm fine. I never felt better.
我挺好 從沒感覺這麼好過
I'm a little tired. I haven't been sleeping...
就是有點累 已經好久沒睡...
Geo, it's normal.
這很正常 老喬
You were with Jim for 16 years.
你和吉姆在一起16年了
I think about Richard every day.
我至今都日夜思念理查呢
It's hard being alone.
孤單是一種病啊
At least you have a job and a life.
至少你還有自己的工作和生活
Let's have a bit of dinner shall we?
去嘗嘗晚餐 如何
Because I've worked so very hard.
我可花了老大功夫來做呢
What are you talking about?
你說什麼啊
Seriously, there no such thing as old anymore.
真的 現在沒有"老"這個說法了
The other day one of my students has called me a senior citizen.
我一個學生有一天管我叫"老年市民"
I wouldn't mind if old didn't exist...
我不在乎"老"的存在與否...
...but I'm not sure senior is what I'm aiming for either.
...但估計"老年"我也談不上喜歡吧
It's all becoming so bland.
一切都變得那麼寡然無味
It's not why I came to America.
這可不是我來美國的原因
It's like a complete breakdown of culture and manners.
彷彿一切文化和禮儀都一夕之間分崩離析了
The young ones have no manners.
那些年輕人根本不懂禮儀
The other day at the car wash
有一天在洗車店
a young man looked me up and down...
一個年輕人上下打量我一番...
...and actually asked me if I was a natural blonde.
...然後居然問我的金髮是不是天生的
What did you say?        I looked him straight in the eye...
你怎麼說      我盯著他的眼睛...
...and said: "Let's just say if I stood on my head...
...說"這麼說吧 我倒立起來的話...
...I would be a natural brunette with lovely breath.
...就是個天生的口氣清新的黑髮美女了"
You didn't!        I did!
不會吧      真的
And the amusing thing was that it went right over his head!
有趣的事他立馬就相信了
You know, you had a mouth on you even back in London.
你早在倫敦的時候就是個刀子嘴
Do you remember that old lesbian who threw her drink over your head...
你還記得那個拿飲料砸你的女同志嗎...
...because you asked her if she was hung like a donut.
...就因為你問人家的洞洞夠不夠用
Geo.
老喬
We could always go back to London. The two of us.
我們兩 隨時都能回倫敦去啊
No, thanks.        You know you miss it.
免了 多謝      你知道你懷念倫敦的
I miss it sometimes.
偶爾為之
Maybe if Jim had lived.
吉姆活著的話或許還有可能
He loved being in England.
他喜歡呆在英國
He asked us to stay the last time we were there.
我們上次回去的時候他就想留下
Do you really think you would have moved?
你認真考慮過搬回去的事嗎
I don't know. It's silly to even talk about it. It was only a fantasy.
不知道 這事說起來都覺得很傻 只是個幻想
What's this?
這是什麼
It's my mother's wedding ring.
我媽的婚戒
I found it a drawer when I was cleaning out.
我清理抽屜時找到的
Charley my dear, you and I are both in need of another drink.
夏莉寶貝 我倆都需要再來一杯
Wait! Wait, wait!
等等 等等
I love this!
我超愛這首
You're insane!        Come on, old man!
你個瘋女人      來嘛 老傢伙
Don't move.
別動
Thank you.
謝謝
Very smooth cigarette move.        I've always wanted to do that.
點煙老手了啊      我一直想這麼點煙
You don't even smoke.
你都不抽煙了
Well, not for the last sixteen years. Jim hated it.
有16年沒抽了 吉姆不喜歡
What's to stop me now? It's not as if he's gonna to kill me.
現在何樂不為呢 也氣不死他了
This is so nice, lying here with you.
這樣和你躺在這兒 真好
Don't you ever miss this?
你會不會懷念
What we could have been to each other?
我們本可以發展成為什麼樣的關係呢?
Having a real relationship and kids?
真正的感情 結婚生子的感情
I had Jim.        I know, but I mean a real relationship.
我有吉姆      我指真正的感情
Geo, let's be honest,
老喬 老實說
what you and Jim had together was wonderful but...
你和吉姆很美妙但...
...wasn't it really just a substitute for something else?
...那也只是別的事的替代品吧
Is that really what you think after all of these years?
這真是你這些年來的想法嗎
You think Jim was just some kind of substitute for real love?
你覺得吉姆於我來說只是個真愛的替代品?
Jim was not a substitute for anything.
吉姆不是什麼的替代品
Do you understand?
你明白嗎
There is no substitute for Jim...
任何人都不可能...
...anywhere!
...替代他
And by the way, what is so real about your relationship with Richard?
再說 你跟理查的關係又多真摯了嗎
He left you after nine years!
他九年後就離開你了
Jim and I were together for sixteen years!
吉姆和我在一起整整16年
And if he hadn't died we would still be together!
他要是沒死我們還會在一起
What the hell is not real about that?
這還他媽不夠真實嗎
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
對不起 對不起 對不起
I know how much the two of you loved each other.
我知道你們有多相愛
I suppose I'm just jealous that you and I never had that kind of love.
我可能只是嫉妒我倆不能那樣相愛吧
Actually, I've never had that kind of love with anybody.
老實說我從沒跟任何人那樣相愛過
I don't think Richard ever loved me...
理查除了喜歡我的外表...
...except for the way I looked.
...估計從沒愛過我吧
And Clay...
還有克雷
I don't know. You raise a child and love it...
我也不知道 你含辛茹苦地養大孩子...
...and then when they are old enough they just leave.
...他們羽翼豐滿了就離開你
Charley, there is nothing wrong with your life.
夏莉 其實你的生活沒什麼問題
You just like feeling sorry for yourself.
但你就是喜歡自憐自艾
It's one of your great pleasures.
這是你的一大愛好
And it's not one of yours?
你不一樣嗎
You're as pathetic as I am.
你跟我一樣可悲
Feeling sorry for myself is definitely not one of my great pleasures.
自憐自艾可不是我的最大愛好
Well, it's not one of mine either.
也不是我的
I don't like feeling sorry for myself one bit.
我一點都不喜歡自憐自艾
I tried to hold onto Richard for so long...
我一直都想留住理查...
...even when it was obvious to everyone but me that it was over.
...即便除了我全世界都知道沒希望了
And now Clay is grown up.
現在克雷也長大了
I mean, what am I doing here Geo? Tell me, what?
我在這兒幹嘛啊老喬 告訴我啊
You have plenty of friends. You'll be fine.
你有這麼多朋友 你沒事的
Yes, I have friends. But none of them need me.
我是有朋友 但他們都不需要我啊
And yes I have you
我也有你
and if you weren't such a goddamn poof we could have all been happy!
你要個該死的同志的話我們就能皆大歡喜了
I only have you now because you lost Jim.
我現在有你 也是因為你失去了吉姆
Soon I'll lose you to someone else.
但很快你又會有別人的
It's not as easy for a woman.
這對女人來說沒那麼容易的
I've done everything the way I was supposed to and...
所有事我都竭盡了全力...
...all I have to keep me company is a bottle of gin.
...而現在身邊只剩下的 是一瓶松子酒
Maybe you should try donuts with your gin.
你或許也該找個洞洞來下酒
Screw you.
去你的
Charlotte, you are dramatic.
夏洛特 你太能演了
I swear you really almost had me.
我差點就當真了
A tiny tear was beginning to form in the corner of my eye.
一小滴眼淚都要從我眼角邊落下了
Now stop it.
別這樣了
You are still breathtakingly beautiful.
你仍舊美得讓人窒息啊
When you can be bothered to get up and out of bed...
只要你肯打起精神從床上爬下來...
...and you stop whimpering about everything for five minutes.
...不要再事事都怨聲連連
Go to London. Change your life.
去倫敦吧 改變你的生活
If you're not happy being a woman then stop acting like one.
做女人做得不開心 就別婆婆媽媽的了
You have all the answers.
你總有一切問題的答案
No, I don't have any to mention.
我沒什麼答案
If you're so smart why don't you have something new in your life?
你要真這麼聰明 何不改變自己的生活
Take that position at Stanford.
接受斯坦福大學的職位
You complain about that little school
你總是抱怨那所破學校
but you could go anywhere you want.
但你其實想去哪都行的
I think what I've done has been worthwhile.
我覺得自己的付出還是有回報的
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
抱歉 抱歉
I shouldn't have said that.
我不該這麼說的
As much as I dread it, I think I will go back to London.
儘管很厭惡 但我想我還是會回倫敦的
Why do you dread it?
幹嘛要厭惡?
When I lived in London last I was young.
我在倫敦時既年輕又新鮮
I was fresh, I was everything.
世界都在我腳下
Coming to America was such a dream, it was the icing on the cake.
來美國就像個夢想 像是蛋糕上的糖霜
Going home is defeat.
回家則是挫敗
None of it really worked out the way I'd planned.
沒有什麼事如我所願的
Most things don't work out the way people plan.
大多數事情都是不隨人願的
You're just living in the past.
你一直活在過去
You need to start thinking about your future.
你得開始考慮未來了
Living in the past is my future.
活在過去就是我的未來
It doesn't have to be yours. You're a man.
你就不必如此 你是個男人
And you're a bore tonight.
而且今晚你是個悶蛋男人
Can't we just feel sorry for ourselves a little bit longer?
我們就不能再自怨自艾一小會兒嗎
Let's have another drink.
再喝一杯吧
I don't think so. I have to go.
算了 我得走了
Come on. Walk me out.        Please, please!
來陪我出去      求你啦
Come on, I have to!        No, this was such fun! No.
好了 我得走了      不行 這麼好玩的
When will I see you again?
我什麼時候能再見你?
Aren't you going to England?        I'll never do that!
你不是要去英國嗎      我絕對不會去的
It's far too much effort.
太花功夫了
Besides,
再說
I don't think Jim would want me to leave you here in LA all alone.
吉姆也不希望我把你一個人留在洛杉磯
Don't worry about me. I'll be fine.
別擔心我
I've got all the answers. Remember?
我有一切問題的答案 不是嗎
What are you doing this weekend?
你這週末幹嘛
I think I might just be very quiet.
很安靜地待著吧
You never really did take me seriously, did you George?
你從沒對我認真過 對吧 喬治
I tried to Charley. Remember? A long time ago.
我試過了 夏莉 記得嗎 很早以前
It didn't really work out, did it?
但沒有結果 不是嗎
No, Charley.
別 夏莉
Sleep tight.
晚安
Patrick, a beer and a packet of Lucky Strike, please.
帕特裡克 來杯啤酒 一包煙
Excuse me.
勞駕
It's too hot in there.
裡頭太熱了
Yes, it is.
沒錯
Would you like a cigarette?        No thanks, I don't smoke.
來根兒煙?      謝了 我不抽煙
This place is really crowded.        Well, it is Saturday night.
這兒人真多      週六晚上嘛
It's usually as bad as this.
通常人都很多的
People normally just stop by and pick someone up
大家基本都是在這裡搭個人
and then head on down the beach.
去海邊折騰
Yeah. It's pretty wild out there.
嗯 這兒挺狂野的
I'm surprised the cops don't break it up.
很奇怪警察還沒來查
Is it always like that?        Since the war ended.
這裡總是這樣的嗎      戰後開始
It's pretty great actually. It's kind of pagan.
其實挺棒的 像是邪教聚會
I'm Jim.        I'm George.
我叫吉姆      我是喬治
Pleased to meet you Jim.
幸會 吉姆
I'm sorry, I'm supposed to meet some friends but I can't find them.
抱歉 我原本是來找朋友的 但我找不著了
I just needed to get out of the house
我只是出門轉轉
but the lure of a cold beer got to me.
但沒禁受住冰啤的誘惑
Do you live hereby?
你住在附近?
Canyon.
在峽谷那兒
For how long?        Since 38.
住了多久了      38年開始
Where are you from?        Colorado.
你哪兒來的?      科羅拉多
I really like it here. It's close to beach.
我很喜歡這裡 離海灘很近·
I think I might stay after I'm discharged.
等我退伍後 我估計就會留在這兒了
I don't know, maybe I'm a bit of a pagan.
或許我也有點邪教氣息吧
After you.        No.
你先請      不
Sorry.
抱歉
Well, hello.        Hi.
你好啊      嗨
Do you buy me a drink?
可以給我買杯酒嗎
I think I'm taken.
我有伴了
Too bad, too bad.
太可惜了 太可惜了
Do you want another beer?
還想再來一杯嗎
Patrick, a bottle of scotch and a pack of Lucky Strikes to go, please?
帕特裡克 打包威士忌和一包煙
Patrick, cancel that.
帕特裡克 不要了
Well, hello Mr. Potter.
你好啊 波特先生
Hello, sir.
你好 先生
What are we drinking?        Scotch.
我們喝什麼?      蘇格蘭威士忌
Okay.
好吧
I come here all the time.
我常來這兒
I live just around the corner, but then you knew that.
我就住在附近 你知道的
On Camphor Tree Lane.
住在坎弗樹路上
You're still carrying that around.
你還帶在身上
One must always appreciate life's little gifts.
人必須對生活賜予的小禮物報以感恩
So, what are you doing here?
你在這兒幹嘛呢
Just out for a ride on my bike.        Is that all?
出來踩踩單車而已      僅此而已?
I don't know.
不知道啊
Were you looking for me?
你是在找我嗎
Maybe. I don't know.
可能吧 我不知道
I feel like my head's stopped up with stuff.
我覺得自己腦袋塞滿了東西
What kind of stuff?
什麼東西
Like, the stuff you were talking about today in class.
譬如您今天在課上說的東西
That is definitely not important.
那些完全無關緊要
No, it is important. Your class is great.
不 很重要的 您的課很棒
But somehow we always seem to get stuck talking about the past.
但我們好像總是在談論著過去
The past just doesn't matter to me.
我不關心過去
The present?        I can't wait for the present to be over.
那當下呢      我等不及讓當下成為過去
It's a total drag.
當下太拖拉了
Well, tonight is the exception.
但今晚是個例外
What?
怎麼?
Tonight, yes! The present, no!
今晚 好! 當下 壞!
Let's drink to tonight.
敬今晚
So if the past doesn't matter and the present is a total drag.
如果過去無關緊要 當下又十分拖拉
What about the future?
那麼未來呢
What future? Cuba might just blow us up.
什麼未來 我們或許就要被古巴炸飛了
Death is the future.
未來就是死亡啊
I'm sorry. I don't mean to be depressing.
抱歉 我不是故意要說得這麼消極的
It's not depressing. It's not depressing, it's true.
不消極 不消極 很真實
It may not be your immediate future but it's what we all share.
這或許不是近期的將來 但卻是我們共同的歸宿
Death is the future.
死亡就是未來
You're right, I guess.
我想 你是對的
If one is not enjoying one's present there isn't a great deal to...
當人無法再當下獲得快樂時...
...suggest that the future should be any better.
...未來的快樂就更是未知的了
Yeah, I've thought that before.
嗯 我過去想過這個
But the thing is you just never know.
但問題是 你永遠無法預知
Look at tonight.
譬如今晚
Actually...
老實說...
...I feel really alone most of the time.
...我時常感覺孤單
You do?        Yeah.
是嗎      嗯
I've always felt this way.
我總是有這種感覺
I mean we're born alone, we die alone.
我們孤單一人出世 孤單一人離去
And while we're here
在這世上
we are absolutely, completely sealed in our own bodies.
我們又被徹底完全地封印在這身體裡
Really weird.
真夠怪的
Kinda freaks me out to think about it.
每每想到這個都會很害怕
We can only experience the outside world
我們只能通過自己扭曲的角度
through our own slanted perception of it.
來體驗世界
Who knows what you're really like?
誰知道你的真是面目呢
I just see what I think you're like.
我看見的只是我認為的你的樣子
I'm exactly what I appear to be.
我完全表裡如一的
If you look closely.
只要你走近了看
You know the only thing that has made the whole thing worthwhile...
你知道嗎 人生最有價值的...
...has been those...
幾個瞬間
...few times
就是當我
that I've been able to really, truly connect with another human being.
真正和他人交心的時刻
I had a hunch about you, sir.
我對您有一種預感 先生
You did?        Yes, sir.
是嗎      對
I had a hunch you might be a real romantic.
我感覺您一定是個浪漫主義者
You know, everyone keeps telling you that...
人人都說...
...when you're older, that you'll have all this experience.
...人老了以後講積累許多經驗
Like it's some great thing.
彷彿那是件很好的東西
That's a load of shit.
這都是扯淡
I think I've actually just gotten sillier and sillier.
我覺得自己是越來越愚蠢了
Really?        Absolutely.
是嗎      絕對的
So, all your experience is useless.
所以 所有的經驗都是無用的
No, I wouldn't say that.
倒也不是
As our friend Mr. Huxley says:
如我們的朋友赫胥黎先生所說
Experience is not what happens to a man.
經驗不是人遇見的事
It is what a man does with what happens to him.
而是人對所遇見事物的反應
Let's go swimming.        Okay.
去游泳吧      好啊
What?        It was a test.
怎麼      那是個測試
I thought you were bluffing about being silly so...
我以為你說變傻的事是在虛張聲勢...
...I said to myself I'll suggest
...所以我想建議你
doing something completely outrageous.
做一件絕對出格的事兒
And if he resists, if he even hesitates
如果你反對 甚至有一絲猶豫
then I know he's full of shit.
那你就是滿口胡言
Well, I wasn't. Were you?
看來我不是了 你是嗎
Hell, no!
當然不是
Come on sir. I'll help you down.
來吧先生 我幫你下去
Let's go.
走
Come on, sir.
來啊先生
Sir?
先生?
That's enough for now, sir.
差不多了 先生
I'm fine.        I'm cold. Come on.
我沒事      但我冷了 走吧
Can we go back to your place, sir?
可以去您家嗎 先生
Of course. Where else?
當然 不然去哪
Where else.        Are you out of your mind?
不然去哪      你傻啊
What's the matter?        You can't get home like that!
怎麼了      你不能就這樣回家吧
We're invisible, don't you know that?
我們是隱形的 您不知道嗎
You know sir, they ought not to let you out on your own.
先生 他們以後不能讓您單獨行事
You're liable to get into real trouble.
你絕對是個惹麻煩的人
I excel at it.
是我的強項
Your forehead is bleeding.
您額頭出血了
The bathroom is just down the hall if you would like to take a shower.
你想洗澡的話 浴室就在走廊盡頭
Aren't you taking a shower too, sir?
您不洗個澡嗎 先生
I'm fine. I'm English. We like to be cold and wet.
我沒事 我們英國人就愛又濕又冷
First, I think that we need to take care of that cut, sir.
我想我們得先處理一下傷口 先生
Do you have any band-aids?
您有創可貼嗎
Going camping, sir?        I'm fine, really.
您要去野營嗎 先生      我沒事 真的
Stay there. I'll be right back.
呆在這兒 我馬上回來
Sit up.
坐起來
Tilt your head back.
仰頭
Well sir, I'm afraid this time you don't have...
先生 這回您恐怕不能以迷幻藥...
...the excuse of mescaline to explain your band-aid.
...作為您貼創可貼的原因了
I think we should get you out of those wet clothes.
你該把濕衣服脫下來
Yes, sir.
遵命
You're not too cold?        I'm great.
不會冷吧      我挺好
Would you like a drink?        A beer, sir. If you have one.
想來一杯嗎      啤酒吧 如果您有的話
I'm afraid that's all we have.
恐怕我就只有這個了
Two beers coming up.
兩杯啤酒 馬上就來
You live here all by yourself, sir?
您一個人住在這裡嗎 先生
I do now.
現在是了
I used to share this place with a friend. He was an architect.
曾經是和一個朋友同住 他是個建築師
Man, guys my age dream about the kind of setup you've got here.
我們這年紀的人做夢都想要有這房子的設施啊
I mean, what more can you want?
夫復何求啊
You get to be left alone and come and go as you please.
可以獨自生活 來去自如
Is that's your idea of the perfect life?
這就是你的理想生活嗎
What's the matter, sir? Don't you believe me?
怎麼 先生 您不相信嗎
If you're so keen on the idea living by yourself...
如果你這麼熱愛獨自一人的生活...
...where does Lois fit into this plan?
...洛伊斯對你來說又是什麼呢
Lois? What's she got to do with anything?
洛伊斯?這關她什麼事?
I got the impression that you and she were together.
我感覺你倆是一對的
Not really. She is kind of cool and...
談不上 她挺酷的...
...we're good friends but...
...我們是好朋友但...
I think what you really want to ask me is if we sleep together.
您真正想問的是我倆有沒有上過床吧
And do you?        We did. Once.
上過嗎      上過 有一次
Why only once?
怎麼只有一次
I didn't say only once, I said once.
我沒說"只有一次" 是"有一次"
Come on, the last thing I want to talk about right now is Lois.
拜託 我現在最不想說的就洛伊斯了
What time is it?
現在幾點了
My watch seems to have stopped.
我的表似乎停了
Do you want me to go?
你想讓我走了嗎
You must be kidding. Go, get us another beer.
開玩笑 再去拿兩杯啤酒來
Is that an order, sir?
這是命令嗎 先生
You're damn right it is.
當然
Pathetic.
可悲啊
Did you say something, sir?
您說什麼了嗎 先生
Why are you here?
你為什麼來這兒
Why did you get to the office and ask secretary for my address?
你為什麼去辦公室 向秘書要我的地址
I just wanted to see you someplace other than school.
我只想在學校以外的地方見到您
Why?
為什麼
Sometimes I think I'm crazy
有時我覺得自己瘋了
cause I see things so differently than everyone else.
因為我看到的世界和眾人不同
I feel like I can talk to you.
我感覺可以向您傾訴
To be honest sir, I was also worried about you today.
老實說先生 我今天很擔心您
Me?
我嗎
What's to be worried about?
有什麼好擔心的
I'm fine.
我沒事
I'm...
我...
A few times in my life I've had moments of absolute clarity.
我人生中 只有幾個醍醐灌頂的瞬間
When for a few brief seconds...
那短暫的瞬間裡...
...the silence drowns out the noise...
...寂靜淹沒了嘈雜...
...and I can feel rather than think.
...我更能夠感覺 而不是思考
And things seem so sharp...
一切都顯得那麼明晰...
And the world seems so fresh...
世界都顯得那麼清澈...
...as though it had all just come into existence.
...彷彿一切都物歸原主了
I can never make these moments last.
但我永遠無法維持這樣的瞬間
I cling to them...
我牢牢抓住它們...
...but like everything they fade.
...但如同萬事萬物 它們都消逝了
I've lived my live on these moments.
我一直活在這幾個時刻當中
They pull me back to the present...
但它們又將我推回當下...
...and I realize that
然後我意識到
everything is exactly the way it was meant to be.
一切都是按照命中注定的軌道行駛
And just like that it came.
就這樣 襲來